MANIMARAN SELVAN

PRODUCT/ENGINEERING LEADER (Belgium Work Permit – D Visa) mselvan@belyf.com | +32 494 80 63 77 | https://linkedin.com/in/maniselvan/

SUMMARY

A software engineer at heart, with 16 years in the field and 6 years in technical product management, I've led initiatives that have significantly boosted efficiency and growth. Known for high-impact strategic decision-making and collaborative leadership, I excel in nurturing high-performing teams and processes.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Co-founded 2 startups (FinTech & ECom).
- Contributed to <u>CloudFix</u> development, yielding \$15M+ internal and \$100M+ customer savings.
- Increased throughput 5x via SLA-driven lean assembly lines.
- Led IT consolidation, saving \$4.3M/year.
- Led post-acquisition of Jive (\$462M), reducing the TCO by 90%.
- Modernized legacy software, reducing millions of LOC to 5K.
- Architected 10+ software platforms from scratch, delivering on time within budget.
- Achieved top 1% in CCAT, demonstrating exceptional cognitive skills.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

Strategic Planning, Leadership & Team Collaboration, Agile & Lean Methodologies, Continuous Improvement, Product Vision & Mission, Vendor Management, Stakeholder Management, Change Management, Testing Methodologies, Decision Making, People Management, Coaching/Mentoring, Crossfunctional Collaboration, Conflict Resolution

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Java, Groovy, Javascript, Python, AWS, GCP, API Gateway, Amplify, Event Bridge, Step Functions, Lambda, Cognito, Cloudwatch, Cloudtrail, Gradle, Maven, Jenkins, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Redis, Athena, OpenSearch, ElasticSearch, Solr, Lucene, Docker, Kubernetes, REST, GraphQL, Swagger, Git, Spring, Akka, React, Node.js, Figma, SES, SQS, SNS, Kinesis, Kafka, Lucidchart, Quicksight, Grafana

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pragya Consulting Services.

Brussels, Belgium (Hybrid)

IT Consultant.

Jul 2023 - Present

- On-site from Jul 2024 Doubled team productivity, increasing project delivery speed by 50% through targeted leadership and mentoring strategies.
- Reduced project delivery times by 25% using Agile and CI/CD practices.
- Successfully led an elite team of 6 engineers to deliver projects on time and within budget, resulting in increased client satisfaction.

Trilogy Enterprises.

Austin, Texas (Remote)

Technical Product Manager, Central TPM founding member.

Aug 2017 - Jun 2023

- Led initiatives saving \$15M+, productized strategies resulting in \$100M+ savings.
- Implemented assembly lines, enabling 24/7 operations for a 5K+ global workforce.
- Co-managed 60+ TPMs with retiring VP, preparing for VP role.
- Developed tools for spec ordering, search, stack ranking, and CTO bootcamps.

Lead Software Engineer, Acting IT Ops Manager.

Jan 2015 - Aug 2017

- Centralized IT Ops for 5K+ global workforce, achieving 85% cost savings.
- Coached and managed 20+ senior SREs, making them deliver 4x value.
- Authored M&A IT transition playbooks, resulting in integrating 15+ acquisitions.
- Set up JIRA workflows and automation, creating an enterprise-wide unified process.

Tissow Technology Ventures.

Chennai, India

Technical Co-founder.

Oct 2013 - Dec 2014

- Conceived, developed, and delivered Humingo, an e-commerce product aggregation platform, in 6 months.
- Modernized Ticketgoose, a bus ticket booking and operator management platform, in 3 months with new tech and simplified architecture.
- Optimized tech operations, reducing TCO by 50%.

Nallan Technology Ventures.

Chennai, India

Senior Associate. Technical Lead.

Dec 2011 - Oct 2013

 Steered the architecture and deployment of Kachyng, a PCI-compliant mobile payments platform with single-click checkout and ads.

EMRG Software Solutions.

Chennai, India

Technical Co-founder.

Aug 2010 – Nov 2011

• Led a team of 10, developing 2 products in the financial information research space.

YuMe.

Chennai, India

Systems Engineer & Java Application Developer

Aug 2008 - Aug 2010

- Managed infrastructure and automated deployments across 6 environments.
- Conducted R&D, developed native mobile apps, and built a lot of PoCs using GWT.

EDUCATION

B.Sc Computer Science, Bharathidasan University, Trichy, India.

2008

Github: https://github.com/mselvan | Blog: https://blog.belyf.com/